American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj
1898-1988
APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - BRACKETED DATES
    - Notes on disposition of A.P.S. collections, [1898?]; 9x6; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
      Scope and Contents note
      A.MS. 1p. Refers to Curators' responsibility, Poinsett collection, Academy of Natural Sciences, renovation of North Room of Hall.
    - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, [1898?]; 9x6; MacCalla & co., inc.
      Phila. L.S.: W[illia]m A Pickell 1p. Correct price charged for setting galleys.
    - Telegram to I[saac] Minis Hays, [1898?]; 5-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
      Princeton, N.J., D. 1p. Will need lantern tonight.
    - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Sept. 5, [1898?]; 7x4-1/2; Edwards, Franklin S.
      [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Inquires about Martin Hans Boyè.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, [1898]; 9x6; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
      A.L.S. 1p. Concerns proofs of paper.
    - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 29, [1898]; 7x4-1/2; Chapman, Henry C. (Henry Cadwalader), 1845-1909
      [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Accepts appointment to committee on H. Allen's papers.
    - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 6, [1898]; 6x4; Chapman, Henry C. (Henry Cadwalader), 1845-1909
      [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Declines appointment to committee on Scott's paper.
    - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, [1898]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Green, Samuel A. (Samuel Abbott), 1830-1918
      Boston, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Corrects error in Justin Winsor's obituary.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 1, [1898]; 7x4-1/2; Allen, Harrison, Jr
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Suggests S.N. Rhoads to read proofs of his father's papers for Transac tions. Thanks for separates. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol.19, pp. 237-266, 267-272.
    - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 21, [1898]; 7x4-1/2; Buti, Rudolph
      Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends translation of fragment of the "Book of the Dead." For enclosure, see Buti, Interesting Fragment..., Oct. 21, 1898.
    - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 14, [1898]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Robins, James W.
      [Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Notice of address.
    - Letter to the [American philosophical society], [1899?]; 10x8; United States. Superintendent of Documents
      Washington, n.d. Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Copies of "Messages and papers of the Presidents, 1789 to 1897" sent to A.P.S. library, as requested by Boies Penrose.
    - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic, Morison], [1899?]; 5- /2x4-1/2; Wagner, Samuel, 1842-
      West Chester, Pa., [1899?] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns memoir of Alexander Biddle. Change of address.
    - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 14, [1899?]; 8x5; Chamberlain, L. T. (Leander Trowbridge), 1837-1913
      New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Orders copy of G.H. Smith's "The theory of the state." Refers to G.F. Edmunds.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Sept.2, [1899]; 6-1/2x4; Cruice, Mary Z.
      Lakeville, Conn., A.L.S. 2p. Asks for extension of leave.
    - Newspaper clippings concerning restoration of Independence Hall and its effect on A.P.S. Hall, [1899]; Independence Hall (Philadelphia, Pa.)
      13 pieces various sizes.
    - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Feb. 28, [1899]; 8x5; Sturcke, Louis
      [New York] A.L.S. 3p., end. Asks about extension of time limit for Phillips prize essays. Written on same sheet is draft of reply from W.V. McKean to Sturcke, March 2, 1899.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 14, [1899]; 7x4-1/2; Witmer, Emma (Repplier)
      [New York?] A.L.S. 1p. Will begin work on Monday on calendar of revolutionary correspondence (published by A.P.S. in 1900).
    - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 25, [1899]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
      Media, Pa., A.L. on postal cars S. 1p. and add. Concerns meeting of Publications Committee.
    - Letter to [the American philosophical society], May 25, [1899]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; American journal of science
      New Haven [Conn.] A.L. on postal card S.: E[dward] S[alisbury] Dana 1p. and add. Sending electrotype at request of E.C. Case.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays], June 13, [1899]; 9x5-1/2; Dana, Charles Edmund, 1843-1914
      Folkestone [Eng.] A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Earl of Crawford's MS. journals shown him by Rosengarten at A.P.S. library.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays], July 4, [1899]; 8x5; Dana, Charles Edmund, 1843-1914
      Hamburg, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Earl of Crawford's journal in A.P.S. library.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays], July 11, [1899]; 8x5; Dana, Charles Edmund, 1843-1914
    - Resolution on the restoration of Independence Hall and Square, Nov. 13, [1899]; 11x8-1/2; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
      [Phila.] Typed copy with MS additionals and corrections. 1p.
    - Concerning William Anderson, a friend of Lafayette, upon the presentation of a photograph to the American philosophical society of a C.W.Peale portrait of Washington which was given to Anderson by Lafayette, [1900]; 13x8; Field, Robert Patterson, -1931
      Typed D. 3p.
    - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, [1902]; 7x5-1/2; Paschall, Mary T. E.
      Doylestown, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from I.J. Wistar about her request to photograph Horologium. For enclosure, see I.J. Wistar to [M.T.E.] Paschall, Aug. 29, 1902.
    - A new cultural centre., [1929]; 8 1/2" x 11"; Dercum, Francis X. (Francis Xavier), 1856-1931
      T.D. 5 leaves. A campaign document.
    - List of portraits restored in 1942 by David Rosen and Hannah Mee Horner, 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
      Typed D. 1p.
    - A short history of the American philosophical society, [1946]; 7" x 8 1/2", 8 1/2" x 11"; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952
      A.D. [59p.] In pencil. Printed (except for four pages): Year Book of the American philosophical society for 1946) Presented by the author, June 1947.
    - The hall of the American Philosophical society., [1949]; 8 1/2" x 13"; Martin, Sydney Errington, 1883-
      Mimeo. D. 10 leaves
    - Letter to the committee on research of the American philosophical society, [1956]; 11x8-1/2; Sarrailh, Jean, 1891-1964
      A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning application by Juan Marichal for grant from the society.
    - List of documents in its possession, [ca. 1815?]; 12-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Historical and literary committee
      D. 2p. and end. (see APS. Historical... committee. Minutes, May 8, 1815-Dec 30, 1816, pp. 11-12.) Items concerning Heckewelder and Indian linguistics, Jefferson, Washington and John and Samuel Adams. FILM 199 FRAME 417
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hays, Jan. 3, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns his paper. Refers to J.B. Smith.
  - Letter to A[rthur] G[eorge] Sedgwick, Jan. 3, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L. 1p. Draft Concerns question about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 4, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Drake, N. F. (Noah Fields), b. 1864
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Concerns his paper on the coal fields of the Indian Territory. Refers to Branner.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 4, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Declines nomination by Ingham for Secretaryship.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 4, 1898; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p. Concerns nomination procedure.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 4, 1898; 9-3/4x6-1/2; Gill, Theodore, 1837-1914
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends paper by Harriet Richardson. Refers to E.J. Nolan.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Jan. 4, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Nansen, Fridtjof, 1861-1930
    LaFayette, Ind., L. on postal card S.: Lionel Clapham, Private Sec. 1p and add. Nansen does not want copies of his remarks at Nansen Meeting, Oct. 29, 1897.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Jan. 4, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Vice President.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Jan. 5, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Drake, N. F. (Noah Fields), b. 1864
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper on coal fields of the Indian Territory. Refers to Branner.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 5, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Gregory, W. J.
    Nichols, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns C.R. Gregory.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, Jan. 6, 1898; 11x8-1/2; International news syndicate
    San Francisco, L. 1p. Asks for information on A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 6, 1898; 10x8; Merrill, S. S. (Samuel Slaughter), 1840-1915
    St. Louis, Mo., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 8, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Edes, Henry Herbert, 1849-1922
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. Asks for membership list.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 8, 1898; 10x8; Gregory, W. J.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 8, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks if Geographical Society of Philadelphia may reprint talk by G.W. Melville. Written on verso is Secretaries' reply. See [A.P.S.] to [Heilprin, Jan., 1898].
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 8, 1898; 5-1/4x8-1/4; Pease, Thomas H.
    Chicago, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 8, 1898; 8x5-1/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for election as Vice President.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 9, 1898; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Willing to serve as Curator.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 10, 1898; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 2p. Concerns lecture by his friend, C.S. Lumholtz.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 10, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Lyon, Victor
    Jeffersonville, Ind., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for price list of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 10, 1898; 10x8; Prince, John Dyneley, 1868-1945
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on Passamaquoddy wampum records. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 479-495.
  - Letter to T. & I.W. Johnson, Phila., Jan. 10, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Thompson, A. M.
    Pittsburgh, Pa., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p., end. by W.V. Mckean Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 11, 1898; 8x4-1/4; DaCosta, Jacob Mandes, 1833-1900
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Councillor.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 12, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Anthropologische Gesellschaft in Wien
    Vienna, A.L.S.: Paulistschke 1p., end. In German Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 12, 1898; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from Lumholtz.
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hayes, Jan. 12, 1898; 10x8; Dall, William Healey, 1845-1927
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledgement of membership certificate.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Jan. 12, 1898; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Olney, Richard, 1835-1917
    Boston, Typed L.S. 1p. Asks requirements of membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 12 -Oct. 15, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Lemcke & Buechner
    L. on postal card 3 items Orders for publications.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Jan. 12, Jan. 20, Feb. 11, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; John Crerar Library
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: C[lement] W. Andrews 3 items 3p. Concerns purchase of A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis [sic] Hays, Jan. 14, 1898; 10x8; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends notes of talk on auroras. Refers to the Franklin Kite Club. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 4-7.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 14, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Hyatt, Alpheus, 1838-1902
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p. Asks to use cuts which illustrated his paper on the "Phylogeny of an acquired characteristic." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 349-647.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 15, 1898; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Haight, James A.
    Olympia, Wash., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 15, 1898; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. with MS. corrections 2p. Concerns printing of R.H. Mathews's paper (in Proceedings, vol. 36?)
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Jan. 15, 1898; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Musselman, William
    Columbus, O., A.L.S. 1p. Has invented a perpetual motion machine.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley], Jan. 15, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Salant, Henry
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 17, 1898; 6-1/2x8-1/4; Bush, R. E.
    Redding, Cal., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 17, 1898; 9x6; Sachse, Julius Friedrich, 1842-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper: "An old broadside, with a reference to the Throne of Congress." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 45-51.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 17, 1898; 8x5; Thacher, John Boyd, 1847-1909
    Albany, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns publication of colonial laws. Refers to Melvil Dewey.
  - Letter to C. Stuart Patterson, Jan. 18, 1898; 6x8-1/4; Garrison, Lindley M. (Lindley Miller), 1864-1932
    Jersey City, N.J. Typed L. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Jan. 18, 1898; 11x8-1/2; International news syndicate
    San Francisco, Typed L. 1p. Thanks for information on A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays?], Jan. 18, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Nolan, Edward James, 1846-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends cuts for H. Richardson's paper on Rocinela. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 8-17.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 18, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Rigby, Ch. C.
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 18, 1898; 10-1/4x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns coming lecture and publication of papers. Refers to election of J.B. Hatcher.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 18, 1898; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    [Vienna], L.S.: [Alfons] Huber 3p., end. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 19, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illia]m H[enry] Wahl 1p. Concerns request for index to publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 19, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for Melville's MS.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 19, 1898; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Lowman, Jesse
    Cincinnati, O., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 19, 1898; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Popular educator
    Boston, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Clipping pasted to sheet. Sends announcement of Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays], Jan. 21, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Allen, Harrison, Jr
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns father's papers received from F.W. True in Washington.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21, 1898; 10x8; Institution of Electrical Engineers
    London, Typed L.S.: F[rancis] W[illiam] Webb 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 21, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Houghton, Walter
    Lynn, Mass., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot supply issues of "Science."
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Jan. 21, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Pennsylvania. State Library
    Harrisburg, Pa., Typed L.S.: William H[enry] Egle, with MS. corrections 1p. Concerns acquisition of State Archives.
  - Telegram to J [sic] Minis Hayes [sic], Jan. 21, 1898; 5-1/4x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., D. 1p. Copy Postpones reading of papers.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 23, 1898; 6-3/4x4-1/2 2-3/4x4-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. 2 encs., 1 of them wanting Sends announcement of Lumholtz's lecture in N.Y. on the Huichol Indians of Mexico.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 24, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/2; K. zoõlogisch-botanisch genootschap te 's Gravenhage
    's Gravenhage, A.L.S.: D. N. Dietz 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 24, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks of Wistar Association for gift of John Vaughan's memorandum book.
  - Telegram to Ella [M.] Morrison [sic], Jan. 24, 1898; 5-1/4x8; Lesley, Susan I. (Susan Inches), 1823-1904
    Milton, Mass., D. 1p. Copy Lesley cannot sign.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Jan. 24, 1898; 8x5; Mitchell, James T. (James Tyndale), 1834-1915
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns meeting of Committee on Historical Manuscripts.
  - Circular to the American philosophical society, Jan. 24, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Valley Forge commission
    Phila., Printed D. 1p. Asks about APS library's holdings relating to Valley Forge encampment, 1777-8. Issued over name of Francis M. Brooke.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis Hayes [sic, Minis Hays], Jan. 26, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brooke, Francis M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns publication of Weedon's Orderly Book. Refers to F.D. Stone's death.
  - Receipt for Treasurer's Bond of Horace Jayne, Jan. 26, 1898; 8-1/4x5, 9-1/2x4; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], D.S. 2p., and add., end.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 26, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Gardner, Emma J.
    Milwaukee, Wis., A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 26, 1898; 8x5-1/4; Willcox, Joseph, 1829?-1918
    Wilmington, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Unspecified matter.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis [sic, Minis] Hays, Jan. 27, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brooke, Francis M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Hopes to see Hays tomorrow.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 27, 1898; 8-1/2x6; Dixon, Samuel Gibson, 1851-1918
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerns committee on H. Allen's papers.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Jan. 27, 1898; 8x5-1/2; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
    Parramatta, N.S. Wales, A.L.S. 4p. Concerns his papers on rock paintings and initiation ceremonies. Regrets death of Harrison Allen. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 466-478, and vol. 37, pp. 54-73.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 27, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Richardson, G. B. (George Burr), 1872-1949
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Asks about paper by N.F. Drake. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 326-419.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Jan. 28, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], Typed L. 1p. Copy Concerns appointment of non-members to committees.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 28, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Returns MS. of Inquisition of Barcelona.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 29, 1898; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns Lumholtz.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 31, 1898; 8x5; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 2p. Hopes to attend C.S. Lumholtz lecture.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 31, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns papers to be read at next meeting.
  - Letter to Charles [B.] Bullock, Jan. 31, 1898; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Copy Appoints him to committee on H.C. McCook's entomological paper. Refers to Fraley, Sharp.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, Jan. 31, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends copy of Fraley's letter on appointment of non-members to committees. For enclosure, see Fraley to Sellers, Jan. 28, 1898.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 31, 1898; 11-1/2x9; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L. filled in in MS. 2p. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Permission to Angelo Heilprin to reprint paper by George Wallace Melville, Jan., 1898; 7x4-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [Phila.,] D.S.: I[saac] Minis Hays, Persifor Frazer, Sam[ue]l P[hillip] Sadtler 2p. Written on verso of Heilprin's request. See Heilprin to Hays, Jan. 8, 1898.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis [sic, Minis] Hays, Feb. 1, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brooke, Francis M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns publication of Weedon's Orderly Book.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 2, 1898; 9x6; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.] Typed L. 1p. Will not attend next meeting of A.P.S.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 2, 1898; 9x6-1/2; Pilsbry, Henry Augustus, b. 1862
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asks issue date of Isaac Lea's Observations on the Naiades. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol.4, pt. 1, pp. 63-121.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 3, 1898; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Holstein, Mark G. (Mark Gabriel), 1873-1952
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Feb. 3, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
    Parramatta, N.S. Wales, A.L. 2p. Directions for printing map of N.S. Wales.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 3, 1898; 9x6; Sherman & Co. (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p. Delay in giving estimate on printing Proceedings.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 4, 1898; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 2p. Appoints Standing Committees.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 4, 1898; 9x6-1/2; Pilsbry, Henry Augustus, b. 1862
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p., end. Asks about Isaac Lea's Observations on the Naiades. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol.4, pt. 1, pp. 63-121.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 4, 1898; 9x6; Sherman & Co. (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p. Withdraws estimate on printing Proceedings.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 5, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    Overbrook [Pa.] A.L.S. 3p. Leaving for Florida until April. Refers to J.C. Morris.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 7, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to Publications Committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 7, 1898; 10-1/2x8; United States Naval Observatory.
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S.: C[harles] H[enry] Davis 1p. Cannot supply a publication for A.P.S. library. Refers to Hydrographic office, Boies Penrose.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 8, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Fraley, Joseph Cresson, ca. 1848-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to Phillips Prize Committee.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 8, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Hildeburn, Charles Swift Riché, 1855-1901
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends a letter.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Feb. 8, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen
    Haarlem, A.L.S.: J. Bosscha, Secretary, on postal card 1p. and add. Exchange of publications.